纽约警局  开门
NYPD. Open up.
我要逮捕杰米·鲁伊斯归案
I have an arrest warrant for Jamie Ruiz.
纽约警局
NYPD.
啊
Aah!
噢哈  嘛嘛嘛嘛
Ho-haw! Ma-ma-ma-maw!
噢哈
Ho-haw!
嘛嘛嘛嘛
Ma-ma-ma-maw!
哈哈哈哈哈哈哈
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
-放松  -放松
- And relax. - And relax.
我做了个梦
I had a dream.
梦中我浮在一片睡莲叶子上
I was floating on a lily pad,
而一队身穿比基尼的瑞典人
and the swedish bikini team
则在朗诵《希特热浪》的好评
was reciting positive reviews of "Naked Heat."
-想必是个美梦  -对啊
- Oh. Well, that must have been lovely. - Yeah.
不过你告诉我们干什么
Why are you telling us this?
因为  多亏了你们
Well, because of you,
我的瑞典天堂变成了猫鸣不断的收容所
my swedish paradise turned into a wailing cat shelter.
我们正在做发声练习
We're doing voice exercises
以增强腹式呼吸
to strengthen abdominal breathing.
在清晨5点吗
At 5:00 a.m.?
准备充足  才能带来富有灵感的试演
Preparation is the foundation of an inspired audition.
啊哈
Ha ha!
我昨晚跟奶奶提过我正在考虑
I mentioned to gram last night that I was thinking about
参加学校音乐剧《火爆浪子》的面试
trying out for "Grease" at my school.
噢  又是"奶奶会乐此不疲
Oh. The old "Gram goes overboard
是因为认定你天生是演员"的老一套
because acting is in your bones" routine.
-正是  -是呀
- Apparently. - Yeah, yeah.
告诉她试演一事太轻举妄动了
Rookie move, telling her about the audition.
其实我也不确定是否有空参加所有社团
I wasn't sure I'd have time with all my other clubs,
只是觉得好玩而已
but I thought it might be fun.
我也不知道她会
I didn't know she'd wake
-天没亮就叫醒我  -我懂
- me up when it was still dark outside. - I see.
一个演员要懂得为演技牺牲
An actor learns to make sacrifices for his craft.
而且  当我们入土为安时
Besides, we'll all have plenty of time to sleep
有大把时间睡觉
when we're dead.
说曹操  曹操到
Oh, speaking of dead.
卡塞尔
Castle.
不  别傻了  我早醒了
Nah. No, no, don't be silly. Of course I was up.
天啊  为什么那么着急
Jeez. What's the big hurry?
死者尸体又不会到处闲逛  对吧
Victim's not going anywhere, right?
这次非同小可
This one's different.
-蕾妮  -听说有个警员遇袭了
- Lanie. - Heard we got an officer down.
-对  通知是这样说的  -谁遇袭了
- Yep. That's the word. - Who is it?
暂时未知  但一个的士司机
Don't know, but a cab driver called 9-1-1
在停车抽烟后报了警
after he parked and stopped for a smoke.
让我看看
Let's see.
胸口中了一枪
Single gunshot wound to the chest.
这位仁兄并没有穿防弹背心
And our guy isn't wearing his kevlar.
能让我靠近看看吗
Mind if I step in there for a sec?
他属于皇后区116号警局
It's from the 116 in Queens.
但这个警章式样老旧
This is an old-style badge, though.
也许他念旧  不愿放下警察生涯的
Maybe he's old-school, didn't want to give up the badge
光辉岁月呢
he built his career on.
卡塞尔  他才20多岁
Castle, he's mid-20s.
你听说过名叫杜奇·豪塞的天才医师吗
You ever heard of a brilliant doctor named Doogie Howser?
是假枪
It's fake.
是龙舌兰酒
That's tequila.
还是劣等酒
That's cheap tequila.
而且这枪该加酒了
And he needed a refill.
一把水枪和一个旧警章
So a squirt gun and an old badge--
显然他不是警察
clearly he's not a cop.
也许他在假扮警察  戏弄无知妇孺呢
Maybe he was impersonating one to prey on vulnerable women.
用一把灌了龙舌兰的水枪吗
Armed with a tequila pistol?
恰恰相反  我倒觉得是女人在戏弄他
Actually, I think women were preying on him.
魔术贴裤子
Tear away pants?
他是脱衣舞男
He's a stripper.
我没找到任何身份证明
I'm not finding any I.D.
但他有车
He does have a car.
在偌大一个城市  大小罪案无数
Of all the cases in the city, and it's a big city,
唯独你遇上脱衣舞男
you catch a male stripper.
是呀  我想我运气好吧
Yeah. Well, luck of the draw, I guess.
对啊  我只是说说而已
Yeah. I'm--I'm just sayin'.
我只是想说  我要坐副驾驶座
I'm just sayin'. Shotgun.
-卡塞尔  没人跟你抢  -那是
- Castle, you're the only one here. - Yes.
这环境让我想起自己的第一间宿舍
This place reminds me of my first dorm room.
死者叫德里克·博克纳
Victim's name is Derek Brookner.
27岁
He's 27.
看  他在存款单背后写了个地址
Hey. He wrote an address on the back of this deposit slip.
"西59街423号  4B"
"423 West 59th. 4-B."
就在街角处
That's right around the corner.
他的尸体正好就在
And his body was found halfway between
这个地址和车之间
that location and this car.
要赌一赌吗  他准是去了这个地方
What do you want to bet that's where he was coming from?
纽约警局  开门
NYPD. Open up!
还在睡呢  走开
Still sleeping. Go away.
打扰了  抱歉
Excuse me. Sorry.
哇
Wow.
哇  哇
Wow. Wow.
那真是...他们...哇
That--they--whoa.
他们会做那个形状的蛋糕吗  那真是...
They make cakes in that shape? That--
又来一个脱衣舞男
Another stripper?
呜  脱掉  呜
Whoo! Take it off! Whoo!
脱掉  脱掉...
Take it off. Take it-- mm-hmm.
各位  我不是脱衣舞男  但我能理解
Ladies, I am not a stripper, though I can understand
你们何以会认错
how you'd make that mistake.
纽约警察  真枪实弹的警察
NYPD--the ones with the real guns.
我们来调查德里克·博克纳的死因
We're here to investigate the murder of Derek Brookner.
我们认为他是你们昨晚派对的娱乐嘉宾
We believe he was your entertainment for last night's soiree.
噢天啊  你是说顽皮警官吗
Oh, my god. Officer Mcnaughty?
我要知道
I need to know
他昨天到来和离开的确切时间
the exact time that he arrived and left yesterday.
-是晚上  -他的舞蹈可长了
- It was dark. - And his dance was long.
不光是舞蹈长
That's not all that was long.
好了  都别闹了
All right, let's pack it up.
我想去一趟警局  你们就会记起来了
I think a trip down to the station will jog everyone's memories.
能中途停下让我们吃个早午茶吗
Could we stop and get brunch on the way?
利伯曼小姐
Ms. Lieberman,
昨晚的事你记得多少
do you remember anything about last night?
德里克昨晚遇害时还穿着舞男装
Derek was still wearing his costume when was killed last night,
人也一直没回到车上
and he never made it to his car,
所以你们是最后见到他还活着的人
which makes your party the last place that he was seen alive.
他昨晚走的时候还好好的
Well, he seemed fine when he left, right?
-我是说...  -对啊
- I mean... - Yeah.
太谢谢你了
Oh, thank you. Mm.
派对上有发生纠纷吗
Were there any problems at the party,
例如吃醋的丈夫或男友突然造访
any jealous husbands or boyfriends that showed up?
没有  只有我们几个女生
No, it was-- it was just the girls.
这次聚会谁安排的
Who arranged the gig?
我  杰米总是对警察情有独钟
I did. Jam-Jamie's always had a thing for cops.
也许你们会想知道
It might interest you to know,
我是自愿辅助凶案科警探的志愿者哦
I'm an assistant volunteer homicide detective myself.
你是怎么预约到他的
How'd you set it up?
就跟你订批萨一样
The same way you'd order a pizza.
我打电话去网上找到的这个有
I called this place that I found online,
大把舞男的地方  报上信用卡号码
mucho men, and gave my credit card.
以3百元一小时
300 bucks an hour to
新潮地欢送我好姐妹出嫁
send my best friend off in style.
他有提过之后要去哪里吗
Did he mention where he was going after that?
他来到时  我们早已烂醉如泥
We were all wasted by the time he showed up.
我是说  他可能有告诉我他的身世
I mean, he could've told me his life story,
但我哪会记得啊
and I wouldn't remember.
等等  单身聚会  脱衣舞男
Wait, a bachelorette party, male stripper,
疯狂买醉  你们肯定有人有拍照
loads of alcohol... One of you had to be taking pictures.
这是最后一部了
Well, here is the last one.
我希望杰米在她老了或厌倦婚姻时
I figured Jamie could refer back to these...
可以回顾这些年少轻狂的照片
when she's old and bored of her marriage.
噢  在喝龙舌兰呢
Oh. Tequila shots.
-她们没把他当人看啊  -算了
- They're treating him like a piece of meat. - It's okay.
这是他的工作  他也很尽兴
It's what he's paid for. He had fun, too.
等等  在这一张停下
Wait, wait, wait. Stop on that one.
你们同一个姿势拍30张
Well, it's a good thing
对于我们的调查工作有帮助
you took 30 pictures of that one pose.
给我放大一下背景
Can you enhance the background?
就那块  几个女生背后
Over there, behind the group.
-那女的是谁  -那是卡米尔
- Who is that woman? - Uh, that's Camille.
她是杰米的一位高中朋友
She's a friend of Jamie's from high school.
从照片看来她和德里克相识啊
It looks as though she and Derek know each other.
没听她说过
She never mentioned anything.
你能放大她的脸吗
Can you enhance her face?
她今早没在公寓里  她去哪了
She wasn't at the apartment this morning. Where is she?
她走了
She left...
就在顽皮警官走后不久
right after officer Mcnaughty.
原来卡米尔·罗伯茨有案底
Turns out... Camille Roberts has a record.
五年前  他的前男友
Five years ago, an ex-boyfriend
在她把他的东西全扔出窗外后
filed a restraining order against her
对她申请了一张禁令
after she threw all his stuff out the window.
作为一个交过几个跟踪狂女友的男人
Well, as a man who's dated several rabbit boilers,
我敢说  绝对会那样做
I can safely say, been there.
是啊  但一张禁令
Yeah, but a restraining order
并不代表她就是凶手
doesn't mean that she's our killer.
是啊  除非他的前男友
Yeah, except that her ex-boyfriend
刚好是本案的死者
happens to be our vic.
在卡米尔·罗伯茨做侍应的咖啡厅找到她
Picked up Camille Roberts at a cafe where she waitresses.
-她在一号审讯室  -好的
- She's in interrogation room one. - All right.
在德里克的公寓有什么发现没
What did we find from Derek's apartment?
多数是老电影海报
Mostly just old movie posters
和一堆唐纳德·特朗普著的经济书籍
and a bunch of Donald Trump books about finance.
也许德里克梦想成为企业家呢
Maybe Derek dreams about being an entrepreneur,
又或者他只是《飞黄腾达》的粉丝
or maybe he's just a fan of "Celebrity Apprentice."
还有别的吗
Anything else?
这里有张日程表  什么也没写
There was a day planner with nothing in it
只有张名片  上面的人名是杰西·曼德勒
but a business card for a guy named Jesse Mandalay.
好  查查看  我去跟卡米尔聊聊
All right, run it. I'll talk to Camille.
简直像场噩梦  真不敢相信他死了
This is like a bad dream. I can't believe he's dead.
为什么德里克一走
Why did you leave the party
你就紧跟着也离开了派对
right after Derek did?
我待不下去了
I needed to get outta there.
你去了哪里
And where did you go?
我回家了  我只想一个人待着
Home. I just wanted to be alone.
你离开之后没见过他
You didn't see him afterwards?
我在街角转了个弯  他就不见了
I turned the corner, and he was gone.
等等  你不会觉得我跟这事有关吧
Wait. You don't think I had something to do with this?
卡米尔  他申请过对你的禁令
Camille, he had a restraining order against you.
那事几年前的事了  只是个误会
That was years ago. It was just a big misunderstanding.
听着  德里克的确伤过我的心
Look, Derek broke my heart,
可我已经想通了
but then I got over it.
这表情可不像已经想通了
This... doesn't look like the face of a person who got over it.
当他走进派对
When he walked into the party
开始脱衣服  我的确很不爽
and started ripping his clothes off, it upset me,
可我没杀他
But I didn't kill him.
好吧  不如咱们来整理一下事实
Okay. Why don't we just go over the facts?
你跟德里克有过一段不稳定的感情
You had a volatile relationship with him,
你和他在同一时间离开公寓
you left the party the same time that Derek left.
接着就有人发现了他的尸体
And then he turned up dead.
你还是直接告诉我到底发生了什么吧
So why don't you just tell me what was really going on?
什么也没发生
Nothing.
我只是无法相信他当了脱衣舞男
I just couldn't believe he was stripping.
为何这么吃惊
And why was that a shock to you?
我们是在表演课上认识的
We met in acting class.
当时所有人都认为他会大红大紫
He was the one everyone thought was gonna hit it big.
当我质问他为什么要放弃梦想时
When I confronted him about giving up on his dream,
他说他跳脱衣舞
he said he was stripping
是因为急需用钱
because he was so desperate for money.
他告诉你为什么了吗
Did he tell you why?
他接了另一个表演
He had some other recurring gig,
可他说他必须退出  因为那会要了他的命
but... he said he had to quit 'cause it was gonna kill him.
-直觉告诉我不是她  -同感
- My instinct says it's not her.  - Mine, too.
但还是让鉴证组给她的衣服
But have C.S.U. check the clothes she was wearing
做个火药残余测试
for gunshot residue.
明白  他跟卡米尔说的那个表演
All right.  Any luck tracking down the gig
有线索了吗
that he was telling camille about?
德里克有一个廉价的经纪人
Derek has a low-rent theatrical agent,
声称已经一年多没给他接过任何活动了
says he hasn't booked anything in over a year.
他发邮件寄来了德里克的表演录影带
He just e-mailed Derek's acting reel.
能看出他的"远大"前途
Here's a taste of his illustrious career.
你们好  我只是随机采访几对情侣
Hey, there. I'm just stopping a few couples
看他们是否听说过一种叫做"聚能王"的产品
to see if they've ever heard of a product called Prolong.
开什么玩笑  我们刚开始服用聚能王
Are you kidding? We just started using prolong.
现在
Now...
一切都...很好很强大了
Things are really... looking up.
聚能王  无需医生处方也可购买
prolong--now available without a prescription.
他也拍过正经片子
he also did serious work.
把你身上的钱都给我
Give me all your money
还有那个车库里的所有东西
and whatever parts you got out there in that garage,
我就考虑不朝你脑袋开枪
and I'll consider not putting one in your noggin'.
比利·格里姆
Billy Grimm is the leader
是一伙野蛮飞车族的头领
of the visi goth motorcycle gang.
如果任何人有这个危险罪犯的消息
If you or anyone has any information on this dangerous criminal,
请速与地方当局联系
please contact your local authority.
靠  我明白这家伙为啥要以脱衣为生了
Damn. I could see why the guy had to strip to pay his bills.
我想  可以肯定地说
Well, I guess it's safe to say
他跟卡米尔提过的那个表演
that the gig that he was telling Camille about
肯定跟他的演艺事业无关
Had nothing to do with his acting pursuits,
总之  你俩去调查"纯爷们儿"经纪公司
So you guys head off to mucho men.
他的单身女郎派对表演就是那里接的
That's the place that booked him for the bachelorette party.
看他是否有定期的脱衣舞表演工作
See if he had any regular stripping gigs...
或有没有什么麻烦  我是贝克特
or troubles there. Beckett.
他也不算很帅嘛
He's not that handsome.
想知道我的意见吗  300块一小时
You want my opinion? 300 bucks an hour--
有点抬举他了
Little steep.
作为这里欣赏过
As the person in this room
这张被单下全部内容的人  我觉得还该加价
that's seen everything under the sheet... bargain.
还有什么发现
What else did you find?
来看看吧
Take a look.
一根头发
A hair?
被害人最近把头发染成了灰白色
Your vic has hair that's been recently dyed gray.
看起来是一次性的
Looks like temporary hair dye
还没完全冲洗干净
that hasn't completely washed out yet.
可大多数男人染发是为了掩盖白发啊
Well, most men color their hair to cover the gray.
有的女人喜欢制服诱惑
Well, some women want officer mcnaughty,
有的则喜欢体贴周到的老男人
and some want an older guy who knows mutual funds.
你懂的  恋父情结
You know, daddy issues.
他染发更像是为了试镜吧
It's more likely he was coloring it for an audition.
说到头发  这有根更重要的头发
Speaking of hair, this is the more important hair
是我在被害人衣物上找到的
That I found on your vic's clothing.
很有可能是凶手的
That could belong to our killer.
金色长发
A long, blonde hair.
有可能是
Well, this could've come
单身派对上的某个女人
from one of the women at the bachelorette party.
起初我也这么想  所以我送去做了化验
That's what I thought until I had it tested.
结果发现了睾丸素
Came back positive for testosterone
和合成类固醇成分
and anabolic steroids.
你们要找的是个金发"男"郎
Your blondie is a man.
翻译：小池  苏小黛  大卫熊  千花  小蛮腰
时间轴：零   后期：瓜瓜   校对：大卫熊   总监：安小七
听着  司徒  你想让我的人抹上油
Listen, Stu, you want my guys oiled up
穿上欧版靴裤去参加蒙太奇泳池派对
in euro booty shorts for the montage pool deck launch,
我已经做出让步了  你也得有点表示才行
You're gonna need to meet me halfway here, buddy.
请随意
Hey, be my guest.
多找几家问问  我们的价格绝对合理
Shop around. It's a fair rate.
听着  我得挂了  有人来了
Listen, I gotta go. I got guys here.
抱歉  推销商总是烦得我蛋疼
My apologies. Promoters are always a pain in my ass.
-劳埃德·桑德斯吗  -我看够运动猛男了
- Lloyd Saunders--  - I'm already up to my ears in a-rods.
不过嘛  你这位朋友...
But, uh, your friend here--
我有一堆女客户疯狂地想要
I got women requesting
《暮光之城》里那小白脸那种类型的
that skinny "Twilight" dude like crazy.
这是均码号  如果太大  加垫一下也行
They're one size fits all. We can pad if need be.
要是害羞的话  卫生间在走廊尽头
Bathroom's down the hall if you're shy.
哥们儿  纽约警察
Hey, NYPD.
关于德里克·博克纳  我们有几个问题要问
We have some questions about Derek Brookner.
对不起  误会了  我们今天在试镜
My mistake. We're doing open auditions today.
我向你保证  这个号我穿合适
I can assure you, this would fit.
人人都这么说  德里克怎么了
That's what they all say. What about Derek?
他被谋杀了
Well, he was murdered.
真可惜  他是我的头牌之一
Wow. Derek was one of my best guys.
我们认为他可能接受了一项工作
We think he took a job
把他卷入了麻烦
that might have got him into trouble.
上个月你为他预订过什么工作
What kind of work did you book for him in the last month?
上个月他在一些有钱人的派对上
He did the occasional, uh,
扮演过几次"俊美来宾"
"handsome guest" at rich people parties.
除此之外  就是些单身女郎派对
Other than that, it was all, uh, bachelorette
吵闹的生日派对之类的了
or rowdy birthday party stuff.
男人的聚会呢
What about any male parties?
没有  德里克只为女顾客服务
Nah. Derek was a women-only guy.
被杀那晚  他跟一个金发男人
He had contact with a blond-haired man
有过联系  那人曾服用过类固醇
who was on steroids the night he was killed.
能想起来可能是谁吗
Any idea who that might be?
可能是他另一份工作认识的人
It could've been someone at his other job.
什么另一份工作
What other job?
除了参加私人活动  他每周还有几晚
In addition to the private gigs, he also danced at a club
要在一家叫做"庞然大物"的俱乐部跳舞
called the package store a couple nights a week.
那里的大部分男人都油光可鉴
Most of those guys are juicing.
有谁跟他关系不好吗
Anyone he didn't get along with?
人们都以为女人才爱搬弄是非
People think women are catty,
可据德里克所说
but, uh, from what Derek said,
那些男人的争斗会让《艳舞女郎》
Those guys would make "Showgirls"
显得就像是课余活动
look like an after-school special.
谢谢
Thanks for your time.
要是你改变了主意的话
Hey, if, uh, you change your mind,
我可以提供尖牙和发胶
I'll provide fangs and some hair gel.
喜欢我性感的肌肉吗
You like my sexy abs?
到"庞然大物"来见我吧
Come see me at the package store...
他们全都油得能榨出汁来
All of 'em are buff enough to be juicing,
可没有一个是长发
but none of 'em have long hair.
更别说金色长发了
Certainly not long blond hair.
也许这些是以前的照片
Well, maybe these are old photos.
有可能他们根据最新的趋势改换了造型
It's possible they change their style based on the latest trend.
那个经纪人提起过
The booking agent mentioned
《暮光之城》的造型现在是主流
the "Twilight" Look is big right now.
也许法比奥的造型要卷土重来了
Maybe the Fabio look's making a comeback.
只有一个办法能查清了
Well, there's one surefire way to find out.
嗷  卡塞尔
Oh, Castle.
真不敢相信你精心打扮了来这种场合
I can't believe you got dressed up for this.
我再问一次
Tell me again
为啥不让莱恩和埃斯波西托陪你来
why Ryan and Esposito couldn't come with you?
我们一致同意  作为自愿的凶杀警探志愿者
We all agreed, as volunteer assistant homicide detective,
只有你能真正的放下身段
you could really sink your teeth
投入到这种地方来进行调查
into this avenue of investigation.
还因为他俩都说"没门儿"
And they called "Not it."
知道吗  自从我跟着你办案以来
You know, ever since I've been following you,
我一直都在梦想有一天你会说
I've been dreaming of the day that you'd say,
咱们去脱衣舞俱乐部捉拿那个坏蛋吧
"Let's go to the strip club and get this dirtbag."
可我从没想过会是这种感觉
I just never imagined it would feel like this.
需要一美元钞票就告诉我一声
Let me know if you need any singles.
真悲剧啊  不远万里跑进城来
It's sad, really. Guy comes to town
想寻找人生的重大转机
Looking for his big break,
梦想着在纽约过上光鲜的生活
Dreams of making it in the apple.
费了这么大劲  可最后得到了什么
What does he get for his trouble?
城市把他嚼烂又吐了出来
The city chews him up and spits him out.
不公平啊  伙计
Doesn't seem right, man.
说得对  当然不公平
Damn right, it doesn't seem right.
我想  他要的只是一点尊重
You know, all I think he wanted was a little respect.
一切都是为了赢得尊重  伙计
It's all about respect, bro.
只是想收支平衡
Just trying to make ends meet,
结果却死在楼梯上
he ends up face down in a stairwell...
穿着丁字裤
wearing a g-string.
好了  给你
Hmm. All right. Here you go.
你这是在干啥
What the hell are you doing?
看够了运动猛男
Up to his ears in a-rods?
我要让那混蛋看看啥叫运动猛男
I got an a-rod for that son of a bitch.
三年大学运动队代表
Three years varsity ball,
两年特种部队铁人三项冠军
Two years special forces triathlon,
还有  2007年纽约警局年历模特
And NYPD police calendar, 2007.
-怎么样  -那只是张集体照
- What?  - It was a group photo.
我收到过粉丝来信
I got letters.
对  一共三封  两封是你妈写的
Yeah, three, two of 'em from your mom.
-只有一封是我妈写的  -必须的
- One of 'em was from my mom.  - Sure.
去他娘的《暮光之城》
"Twilight" my ass.
卡塞尔
Castle?
嗨  宝贝儿
Hey, honey.
你找到我了啊
Oh, you found me.
我这儿正跟丹尼斯聊你呢
I was just telling Denise here about you.
这是我女友
This is, uh, my girlfriend,
今晚来这儿是她的主意
Whose idea it was to come here tonight.
她很有冒险精神  不瞒你说  有一次...
She's very adventurous. You have no idea. There's...
感谢上帝你找到我了
Thank god you found me.
天啊  这些女人就像食人鱼一样
Oh, my god. These women are like piranha.
我刚刚和其中一位酒保谈过
So listen, I just talked to one of the bartenders,
其说辞与演出代理人一致
who confirms the booking agent's story
德里克的确和其中一名舞者关系闹得很僵
that Derek was having troubles with one of the other dancers.
情况是  一个叫做汉斯的人
Apparently some guy named Hans was upset
对于德里克抢了头牌的位置而怀恨在心
that Derek was getting the headliner shift.
他有动机  还有不利证据指向他
That gives us evidence and motive.
我们去后台  去找那个汉斯
Let's go backstage. Grab us some hans.
不必了  亲爱的
No need to, honey.
他马上就出场了
He's in the next act.
不是吧  消防队员
Firemen, really?
太老套了吧
That's not a little cliche?
老天啊
Oh, god.
这些家伙没看过日光浴容易导致皮肤癌
Haven't these guys got the memo about the correlation between
-的备忘录吗  -你就好好享受嘛  卡塞尔
- suntanning and skin cancer? - Can you just relax, castle?
我们得搞清楚哪个是汉斯
We gotta figure out which one is Hans.
搞清楚了
Yeah.
纽约警局
NYPD.
从台上下来
Please come off the stage.
-好啊  -不不  只让你下来  汉斯
- Uh-huh. - No, no. Not you. Just Hans.
伙计们  别扭了  我是警察  真的警察
Guys, knock it off, okay. I'm a cop. A real cop.
这样一点都不好玩  都冷静点
Look, it's not funny. Now cool it.
做的过火了吗
Too much?
德里克...是个小贱人
Derek... was a little bitch.
你知道他花多长时间
Do you know how many hours he spent rehearsing
排练我们的"加勒比海盗"舞蹈吗
our privates of the caribbean routine? Hmm?
一次都不来
Zero.
他总是扯淡说
He was all artsy-fartsy
他要参加试镜或是话剧要排练什么的
with his acting auditions this and play rehearsals that.
汉斯·范曼斯沙夫特才是那个
Hans Von Mannschaft is the one
每晚都在认真干活的人
doing the real work out there every night.
汉斯·范曼斯沙夫特
Hans Von Mannschaft?
你这个艺名真赞啊
That's a hell of a stage name.
我告诉你  我可是骄傲的
I'll have you know I come from a long line
范曼斯沙夫特后裔
of proud Von Mannschafts.
你的祖先有过因谋杀进监狱的先例吗
And have any of them served time for murder?
等等  等等  谋杀
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Murder?
小心  汉斯  露出自己的新泽西口音了
Careful, Hans. Your New Jersey is starting to show.
这个地方给人梦幻的感觉
This place is about fantasy.
女人来这是为了解脱
Women come here to escape.
我这是为了表演
This is part of the act.
表演包括除掉竞争对手吗
Does that include getting rid of the competition?
德里克于昨晚被枪杀
Derek was found shot and killed last night,
我们在他的衣服上找到了你的头发
and we found one of your hairs on his clothes.
你刚刚也承认了你们不和
And you just admitted that the two of you were rivals.
不和  女士  我成天
Rivals? Lady, I spend my days
穿着小裤衩取悦女人
with women shoving bills down my shorts.
你真的认为我会因为关系不和就杀人吗
Do you really think I'd kill somebody over that?
这也改变不了现实  我们判定
That doesn't change the fact, we can place you
-你去过犯罪现场  -就因为发现我的头发吗
- at the scene of the crime. - Because of my hair?
那只能证明我们的服装
All that proves is that we keep our costumes
都装在一个大衣柜里面
in the same big closet backstage.
见鬼  我每天涂两次米诺地尔[防脱产品]
Hell, I'm using minoxidil twice a day
-就是为了别掉头发  -昨晚你在哪
- just to keep it on my head. - Where were you last night?
我在台上表演  从晚八点一直到凌晨一点
I was onstage doing shows from 8:00 till 1:00.
有100多个女人可以为我作证
There are over 100 women who witnessed it.
他的不在场证明和他的腹肌一样"结实"
His alibi is as hard as his abs.
你们和他的女友谈过吗
Did you talk to his girlfriend?
什么女友
What girlfriend?
一个很是喜欢他的富婆
Some rich cougar who was obsessed with him.
很显然德里克是为了钱才和她在一起的
It was obvious Derek was using her for the money,
但是我想可能是他受够了她  便抛弃了她
But I guess he got fed up with her and kicked her to the curb.
-你怎么知道的  -她总是
- How do you know that? - She always
把很贵的花送到他的更衣室
sent expensive bouquets to his dressing room.
但是上周
and then last week,
这个月的头一回  没有花了
for the first time in months, no flowers.
嘿  什么情况  没有一美元的钞票了吗
Yo, what's up? You run outta singles?
汉斯说得对  我们找到一个花店
Hey, Hans was right. We found a flower shop that confirmed
确认过去四个月每周都有送花去
weekly deliveries for the past four months.
我就知道询问那个范曼斯沙夫特  会找到线索的
I knew if we beat on Mannschaft, something would pop.
花是谁送的
Who were they sent to?
付款的是属于48岁瑞贝卡·达顿的
They were charged to an Amex
一家证券事务所
belonging to Rebecca Dalton, 48.
她住在63街和麦迪逊街交口处
She lives at 63rd and Madison.
看看这个  财富500强在2005年的时候
Check this out. Fortune 500 lists Rebecca Dalton's husband
称瑞贝卡·达顿的老公拥有出版业帝国
as having a publishing empire in 2005.
瑞贝卡曾经是T台模特
It says here that Rebecca used to be a runway model.
她结婚了  有料啊
She's married. Juicy.
不不  不是这样的
Mnh-mnh. Not anymore.
她的丈夫几年前去世了
Her husband died a couple of years ago.
把整个帝国的财产都留给了他悲伤的妻子
Left his entire fortune to his grieving wife.
更有料啊
Even more juicy.
瑞贝卡年轻的时候结了婚
Rebecca marries young,
自己的青春年华浪费在
spends her 20s and 30s under the thumb
一个富有却支配欲很强的丈夫手中
of a rich yet domineering husband.
他一死  我们这位上了年纪的美人
Well, he dies, leaving our aging beauty
重获自由  不再受无爱婚姻的桎梏
finally freed from the shackles of a loveless marriage.
一晚她和以前做模特的朋友外出聚会
One night she's out with her ex-model posse.
她认识了迷人英俊的德里克
She meets the very charming, very handsome Derek.
她在多年之后
Well, for the first time in years,
再次感觉到了活力
she feels... alive again.
但是他们的感情在德里克找到了
The relationship reaches its inevitable conclusion
和自己年龄相仿的伴侣之后无疾而终
when Derek meets someone closer to his own age.
那种心痛
Well, the--the heartache
使得瑞贝卡如此的发狂
has Rebecca so distraught
导致她因为嫉恨杀死了德里克
that she kills Derek in a jealous rage.
如果她无法拥有他
If she couldn't have him...
别人也休想拥有他
Well, then no one could.
你们去"庞然大物"之前
Did you go home and watch "Sunset Boulevard"
你不会是跑回家看了一遍《日落大道》吧
before your little trip to the package store?
感谢你娱乐性很高的故事
Thank you for your always entertaining stories,
但是我认为还是明天早上问问瑞贝卡
but I think we will get a lot closer to the truth
才是解决问题的最好方法
if we just ask Rebecca a few questions tomorrow morning.
-但是故事很精彩吧  -是啊  我喜欢
- It was good, though, right? - Yeah, I liked it.
-是啊  -不错
- Yeah. - It was, yeah.
-怎么说呢  -我回来了
- Well... mm-hmm. - Hey.
你们不会是背着我喝根汁汽水
Are you guys celebrating with root beer floats,
庆祝胜利吧
and nobody told me?
我倒是希望如此  我和凯莉·伯顿
I wish. They narrowed the part of Sandy
成为了扮演珊迪的最后候选人
down to Kelly Burton and yours truly.
还没有最后定夺  我很紧张
We're taking a little break, but I'm really nervous.
所以我们才穿着戏服练台词
That's why we're running lines in costume.
明天你会很自然的发挥的
Tomorrow it'll be second nature.
我看出来了  你到你的时间胶囊里
Well, I see you've dug up your time capsule
-找回了你的裤子  -我告诉你
- to resurrect those pants. - I will have you know,
穿着这条裤子我可是度过了不少欢乐时光
I had some of my best memories happen in these pants.
-恶心  -恰恰恰
- And ew. - Cha.
我去睡觉了  明天是大日子
I'm off to bed. Big day tomorrow.
-好的  亲爱的  好梦  -谢谢
- Okay, darling. Sleep well. - Thank you.
不管怎样  我都为她感到骄傲
Whatever happens, I am so proud of her.
她无所畏惧
She is fearless.
知道吗  老妈
You know, mother,
我觉得你给阿丽克西斯做了好榜样
I think you're a really good influence on Alexis.
怎么回事  孩子  发烧了还是精神错乱了
What's with you, kiddo? Fever, delirium?
不不不  我说真的呢
No, no, no, I'm serious.
你总是...很专注
You have always been... dedicated,
这种坚持很难做到的
and that--that can't have been easy.
我也不是一路顺风顺水啊
Well, yeah, it hasn't always been days of wine and roses.
我也做过那些见不得人的工作
I had to take a lot of less-than-prestigious jobs
-来支撑自己的演艺事业  -比如说
- to ply my craft. - Such as?
上帝啊  我演过小精灵
Oh, lord. I played an elf. Ugh.
那是在圣诞老人小村  还扮过自由女神像
Santa's Village. Uh, lady liberty.
在一个税务中心外面扮自由女神像
Lady liberty outside some low-rent tax service,
还有就是  哦不
and then--oh, no.
最烂的工作  我做过最烂的工作
The worst job-- the worst job I ever had--
我完全做不好  他们也不喜欢我  真是...
I was terrible at it, they hated me, it just--
我...那真是...简直是
I was--it was absolutely the--just completely--
什么工作
What was it?
做秘书
Secretary.
那活儿你做不来的
You'd be terrible at that.
太烂了
Awful.
我确定很多美男都走过这个大厅
Oh, I'm sure many a pretty boy have walked this hall.
用不了多久  他们就会发现
Doesn't take 'em long to realize that they're trapped
他们落入了一个中年熟女设下的陷阱
in the strangling embrace of an aging spinster.
我们还是先和她谈谈
Maybe we should talk with her
你再开始写电影剧本吧
before you start writing the lifetime movie.
嘿  快速选择演员阵容  艾什顿和黛米
Ooh. Quick casting idea-- Ashton and Demi.
纽约警局  我们来找瑞贝卡·达顿
NYPD. We're here to speak with Rebecca Dalton.
请进
Please come in.
我是达顿女士的律师  迈克尔·格兰特
I'm Ms. Dalton's attorney, Michael Grant.
我会在询问中旁听
I'll be sitting in on the interview.
我在一次筹款活动中认识了德里克
I bumped into Derek at a fund-raiser.
后来他承认是主办方请他来
He later admitted that he had been hired by the host
施展魅力  促使人们在缄默拍卖中竞价
to mingle and encourage people to bid on the silent auction.
但是为时已晚  我已经喜欢上了他
But it was too late. I already liked him.
你发现他是脱衣舞者反应如何
And when you found out he was a stripper?
我没有发现  是他告诉我的
I never found out. He told me.
这种事他不会瞒着我的
He never hid any of that from me.
这工作使得他早上可以去搞他的演艺事业
It gave him the freedom to pursue his acting career,
可以在白天去试镜  他的坚韧值得我尊敬
audition during the day, and I respected his tenacity.
因为什么分手了
What caused the breakup?
关系自然而然走到了尽头
The relationship had run its course.
听起来像是在说谎
That sounds like something that you would say
尽管我不知道你是在骗我们  还是在骗自己
when you're lying, either to yourself or to us.
你不会是以为他的死和我有关吧
You don't really think I had anything to do with his death?
我只是觉得在你们分手后不久  他就遇害
I just find it curious that right after you've split up,
这一点很可疑
he's found dead.
谁提出的分手
Who broke it off?
-我的委托人  -因为什么
- My client did. - Why?
上周  他管我的委托人借两万五千美元
Last week, he asked my client to borrow $25,000.
我早就知道  把钱和情感混在一起
I've learned, it's never a good idea
可不是什么好主意
to mix relationships with money.
意图会变得模糊不清
Intentions get foggy.
-他为什么需要那笔钱  -他不肯说
- And why did he need the money? - He wouldn't say.
更糟的是  他显得很冷漠
And to make matters worse, he seemed distant.
你认为他出轨了
You thought he was cheating.
有过这个想法  不是什么值得炫耀的事
It occurred to me, and I'm not proud of it,
但是我请迈克尔雇了私家侦探
but I had Michael hire a private investigator.
我必须知道真相
I had to know.
当我的委托人看到了照片  她意识到
When my client saw the photographs, she realized
德里克和一些声名狼藉的人混在一起
Derek was mixed up with some disreputable people.
你为什么会觉得那是坏事
And what made you think it was a bad element?
因为德里克不会和那种人有来往的
Because Derek didn't hang out with people like that.
他是来自密西根的好男孩
He was a good kid from Michigan.
如果他们跟谋杀案有任何关系
If they had something to do with his murder,
我会改变主意
I'd have taken my decision back
立马把钱借给他
and given him the money in a heartbeat.
我要看看那些照片
I'm gonna need to see those photos.
私家侦探拍到
The P.I. took a picture
德里克跟这个女人说话
of Derek talking to this woman,
然后他跟这女的去了另一个地方
and then he followed her to the next location.
那么德里克在家附近
So Derek is outside his apartment
跟"炸弹"麦吉说话
talking to Bombshell Mcgee.
-这有什么危险的吗  -等等
-What's so dangerous about that? - Wait a minute.
莱恩  你能将德里克的表演录像调出来吗
Ryan, can you pull up Derek's acting reel?
天啊  看一次就够要命的了
Man, once was bad enough.
把你身上的钱都给我
Give me all your money and whatever parts
还有那个车库里的所有东西
you got out there in that garage,
我就考虑不朝你脑袋开枪
and I'll consider not puttin' one in your noggin'.
比利·格里姆是
Billy Grimm is the
这跟照片上是同一个人
That's the same guy as the mug shot.
比利·格里姆
Billy Grimm
西哥特机车族的老大
leader of the visigoths motorcycle gang.
比利·格里姆的犯罪记录
Billy Grimm's rap sheet.
勒索  用致命武器袭击他人  持械抢劫
Extortion, assault with a deadly weapon, armed robbery.
当德里克的那集
When Derek's episode
《全美最危险的罪犯》播出后
of "America's most dangerous criminals" aired,
格里姆被指控意图谋杀
Grimm had an attempt murder warrant out.
显然有人欠他钱  于是他将那人
Apparently some guy owed him money, so he chained him
绑在摩托车后面  拖上了长岛高速公路
to the back of his bike and dragged him down the L.I.E.
变态格里姆怎么没关进牢里
Why isn't this psycho Grimm in jail?
他进过了  事实上  他就是因为
He was, as a matter of fact, he was caught
德里克在节目中再次扮演他才被逮捕的
because of Derek's reenactment on the show.
但那个被绑住的家伙改变了主意
But the guy he chained to his bike had a change of heart,
决定不指控他  于是格里姆最近被释放了
refused to testify, so Grimm was recently released from jail.
如果这家伙做事这么疯狂
Well, if this guy was such a whack job,
那德里克为什么还要跟他的手下说话
what was Derek doing talking to one of the members of his gang?
我知道答案  格里姆被捕时
I think I can answer that. When Grimm was arrested,
一名记者问他因为一个
a reporter asked him how he felt
电视节目而被捕有什么感觉
about being brought to justice by a TV show.
他发誓要报复那些令他进监狱的人
He swore vengeance against those who put him jail,
尤其是  格里姆说
especially--and Grimm says,
那个令我看起来像个小丑的演员
"that actor that made me look like a clown."
我可以从以前特遣队的经验
I can tell you this about visigoths
告诉你  西哥特人
from my gang task force days
他们很注重自己的身份
they're serious about their colors.
这些背心上的补丁
These patches they wear on their vests?
不是校队制服上的字母
They're not varsity letters.
他们可是得付出血汗才能得到的
They gotta spill blood to get 'em.
但却有家伙穿着这个出现在电视上
And some guy wearing 'em on national tv?
那么她是在设计他
So she was setting him up...
为了谋杀他
for murder.
放松  卡塞尔  它被锁链绑着
Relax, Castle. It's on a chain.
纽约警局
NYPD.
这是你的老妈么
This your old lady?
这是私人机构
This is a private establishment.
那么我们将这事私密地处理
Well, then we'll try to keep this private.
比利·格里姆
Billy Grimm.
鲍比
Bobby!
唷
Yo!
我需要问你一些问题
I need to ask you a few questions
是关于你和德里克·博克纳的关系
about your association with Derek Brookner.
没听说过这家伙
Never heard of the guy.
我只要一通电话  管理机动车盗窃的部门
I make one phone call, and auto theft detail is down here
就会来查车辆识别号码
checking vin numbers.
他们只需要找到一个失窃的尾灯  你就玩完了
They find so much as a stolen taillight, you're violated.
你现在想起他了吗
You remember him now?
我想起来了
You know, I do.
他看起来像是好孩子
He seemed like a good kid.
他死了  我敢打赌你跟这事
He's dead, and I'm willing to bet that you
-脱不了干系  -德里克毁了你的形象
- had something to do with it. - Derek wore the colors,
而且你因为这节目被捕了
and you got popped 'cause of the show.
这就是为什么你找人干掉他
That's why you put a contract out on him.
我或许是有些恼火
Well, I might have been a little pissed off.
但这孩子懂得尊重别人
But the kid came with respect.
他带来了捐款
He brought a donation.
捐款  你是什么  救世军吗
A donation? What are you, the Salvation Army?
我也很惊讶  但我想德里克可能认为
Well, I was surprised, too, but I guess Derek felt
两万五千美金能帮助解决我的日常开支
25 g's might help bring down my overhead.
你真的觉得我会相信
Do you really expect me to believe
一个苦苦挣扎的演员能有足够的钱
that a struggling actor had enough money
捐献两万五千美金给你吗
to give you 25 grand outta nowhere?
这是事实
That's what happened.
他的钱从哪来的
Where did he get the money?
我又没看过他该死的纳税申报单
I didn't ask to see his frigging tax return.
他的钱从哪来并不关我的事
Ain't my business how he got the money.
他带给我现金  这就够了
He brought the cash, and that was good enough.
难道你忘记了勒索的那部分吗
Aren't you forgetting the part about the extortion,
你让你女友替你捎话
the part where you asked your girlfriend to deliver a message
叫德里克付你两万五千美金
that Derek had to pay you 25 grand?
你给他一周的期限去筹钱
You gave him a week to do it.
他没法筹到钱
He couldn't scrape together the money,
于是你杀了他
and so you killed him.
宝贝  这是怎么回事
Babe, what is this?
我可以解释
I can explain.
你干嘛跟这混蛋说话
What the hell were you doing talking to that bitch?
听着  你出狱时
Listen, when you got outta jail,
我担心你会做出什么傻事
I got nervous you were gonna do something stupid,
所以我跟那孩子说  如果他不想惹麻烦
so I went to talk to the kid, told him if he didn't want
就先带钱来找你
any trouble, he'd bring you a preemptive donation.
你警告他了  所以他才会出现吗
So you warned him? That's why he showed up here?
我不能再次失去你
I couldn't stand the thought of losing you again.
除非我死了  否则我不会再让你进监狱的
The only way you're going back to jail is over my dead body.
布基熊熊
Pookiebear...
这是我听过的最浪漫的话了  宝贝
That is the most romantic thing I've ever heard, baby.
过来
Come here.
嘿  比利的不在场证明证实了
Hey. Billy's alibi checked out.
酒保证实他直到打烊前都在打台球
Bartender confirmed that he was shooting pool till close.
是的  我们跟总督察谈过了
Yeah, and we talked to our C.I. and there's no word
没有证据显示我们的被害人借高利贷
of our victim hitting up any of the usual loan sharks.
我想知道一个脱衣舞男怎么能这么快
You know what I want to know is how a stripper comes up
-筹到这么多钱的  -开个黄金户口
- with that kind of cash in such a hurry? - Cash-n-gold.
卡塞尔  你看太多电视导购节目了
Castle, you watch way too many infomercials.
我们也调查了他在JLP银行的户口
We also checked his account at JLP Bank Corp.
他的账户余款
He never carried an account balance
从没超过几千元
of more than a couple thousand dollars.
等等  如果德里克在JLP银行有户口
Wait a minute. If Derek had an account with JLP Bank Corp,
为什么他的车里会有联邦堡垒的存款单
why was there a deposit slip from Rampart Federal in his car?
我们去查出德里克付比利钱的那天
Let's run down withdrawals for 25 grand
从联邦堡垒分行提取了
from rampart federal branches
两万五千美金的账户吧
for the day that Derek paid Billy.
我不晓得你怎么会漏了这个
I don't know how you missed that.
93街的联邦堡垒处理过同数额的交易
Rampart federal on 93rd posted a transaction that size,
由杰西·曼德勒在那天11点53分提取
made by a Jesse Mandalay at 11:53 a.m. that day.
德里克的其中
Derek had a card
一本书里夹了杰西·曼德勒的名片
for Jesse Mandalay tucked inside one of his books.
我打了上面的电话  没能连接上
I called the number. It was disconnected.
有可能就是曼德勒
It's possible that Mandalay
借了钱给德里克
was the one that loaned Derek the money.
或许德里克以为他可以弹性地还债
Maybe Derek thought he was on a flexible payment plan,
需要多点时间  于是曼德勒杀了他
needed more time, and Mandalay killed him for it.
银行现在正将曼德勒取款的监控录像
Well, the bank is sending over the surveillance footage
发过来
of Mandalay right now.
来了  这就是曼德勒正在提款
Here we go. There's Mandalay taking the cash.
没错  这西装看上去
Yeah, by the looks of that suit,
放高利贷的工作利润不错
the loan business must be pretty lucrative.
-好了  来看这家伙的脸  -等等等等
- Okay, let's see this guy's face. - Wait, wait, wait.
那不是杰西·曼德勒
That's not Jesse Mandalay.
那是染了灰发的德里克
That's Derek with gray hair.
杰西·曼德勒就是德里克
Jesse Mandalay is Derek.
分行经理说德里克提款的户口
The branch manager said that Derek withdrew money
叫做太阳火有限公司
from an account called Sunfire Limited.
那他另一个身份杰西·曼德勒呢
And his alter ego Jesse Mandalay?
是签署者  但其他的仍然是一个谜
Was the signatory, but the rest is a mystery.
太阳火连接到一个海外帐户
Sunfire is linked to an offshore account,
他们唯一能追查到的人就是曼德勒了
and the only person that they can trace it to is Mandalay.
这些钱的踪迹引向到一个不存在的人
A money trail that leads back to a man who doesn't exist.
德里克染了头发
Derek was dyeing his hair gray,
穿上名贵西装让自己看起来很有成就
wearing fancy suits to look more distinguished,
而且他在看财经和投资的书籍
and he was reading books on finance and investment
是为了替某人饰演杰西·曼德勒的角色
so that he could play the role of Jesse Mandalay for someone.
但为什么要雇一个演员去饰演商人
But why hire a struggling actor to play a businessman?
我调查了些中国企业的资料
I did some research on chinese companies that would,
有时候会雇请白人
uh, sometimes hire a-a white man
去扮演主管参加剪彩仪式
to pose as an executive at, uh, ribbon cutting ceremonies,
股东大会
uh, shareholder meetings,
只是为了令投资者产生信心
just to instill confidence in investors.
同样  一个大学生寻求创业投资
Likewise, a college student seeking Venture Capital
有时候会雇请看起来成熟的骗子
will sometimes hire an older-looking shill,
你知道  有的人看起来比较杰出
you know, someone who looks more, uh, distinguished
去帮助他们筹集资金
to help them secure money.
如果德里克是被雇去当公司门面的
So if Derek was hired to be the face of the company,
那么不管是谁雇他
then whoever hired him
就是幕后操控银行户口的人
was the person behind the bank account.
我们追查最近
Let's see if we can track down any checks
存入太阳火有限公司的支票
that were deposited into sunfire limited recently.
如果我们能追踪到那些钱  或许我们就能
If we can trace the money, maybe we can figure out
弄清楚杰西·曼德勒这角色的存在价值了
if Jesse Mandalay was a role to die for.
是的  那是曼德勒  百分之百  怎么了
Yeah. That's Mandalay. 100%. Why?
隆巴多女士  我们想知道你几天前
Miss Lombardo, we need to know about the $10,000 check
有没有写过的一张一万美金的支票给他
that you wrote him a couple of days ago.
当然  那钱花的太值得了
Sure. Best money I ever spent.
那些钱是干什么的
What was the money for?
一个令人兴奋的投资机会
An exciting investment opportunity.
我的死党萨米听她男友罗尼从
My girlfriend Sammi heard from her boyfriend Ronni
他表兄保利那儿听说的
who heard from his cousin Pauly
有关曼德勒先生的介绍
about mr. Mandalay's presentation.
那么他推销的是什么
And what was the sales pitch?
美丽的布雷弗曼阁楼
The beautiful Braverman lofts
座落在田园诗般的霍博肯河边
in idyllic riverfront Hoboken.
曼德勒就在那儿吗
And Mandalay was there himself?
他告诉我们一个好消息
He gave us the awesome news
如果我们那天下订一万美元
that if we put down the $10,000 that day,
我们可以以四十万的价格卖下阁楼
we could purchase a loft for $400,000.
河边的阁楼吗
A riverfront loft?
我知道  太神奇了不是吗
I know. Amazing, right?
呃...的确是很神奇  没错
Uh, um... Amazing is-- is one word for it, yes.
只有笨到一定地步的人
Yeah, you have to be, like, a freakin' bonehead
才会错过这么划算的买卖
to pass up on a deal like that.
介绍会那天还有别人
Did anyone else at the presentation hand over
给曼德勒支票吗
a check to Mandalay that day?
大家都给了  我爸知道我从我的
Uh, everyone. My dad was pretty butt sore
大学基金里拿了钱出来的时候  很不爽
that I took the money out of my college fund,
但是当我跟他解释说
but when I explained that it would fold
买进卖出会大赚一笔的时候
into the purchase price,
他就发现我们一家人都有做生意的头脑
he recognized that business smarts runs in our family.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
曼德勒说合同晚点寄给你  对吧
The, uh, the contract is in the mail, right?
就是这了  布雷弗曼套房
Yeah, this is it. The Braverman lofts.
那肯定就是样板房了
And that must be the showroom.
四十万就可以买一套吗  那我要两套
$400,000 for one of these? I'll take 2.
卡塞尔  走了
Castle, let's go.
不好意思
Excuse me.
有什么可以帮你的吗
Can I help you?
纽约警署  这里的负责人是谁
NYPD. Who's in charge here?
是我  我是开发商  伯特·克雷姆
I am. I'm the developer -- Bert Kramer.
我们是为了杰西·曼德勒一事来的
We're here about Jesse Mandalay.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
很不巧我认识  他给我惹了一堆麻烦
Unfortunately, and if I ever see that guy again, I'm gonna
要是让我再看见他
bust him in the jaw for
-我就打歪他的下巴  -让我猜猜
- all the crap he put me through.  - Let me guess.
-他利用了你  -没错
- He took advantage of you.  - Damn right.
他假装这是他的楼盘  然后就卖上了
He tried to sell my friggin' property like it was his.
他来的时候说自己是地产经纪
Showed up here claiming to be a real estate agent,
吹嘘自己卖过多少房产
and he had this rap about all these properties he's sold.
于是你就给了他这栋房子的钥匙
And you gave him access to the building?
他说他要带一车客户过来
Well, he wanted to bring a caravan of clients through,
还坚持一定要在周日
and he insisted it be on a Sunday,
于是我就把开门的密码告诉他了
so I gave him the lockbox codes.
你怎么发现他是骗子的
How did you find out he wasn't legit?
自从那天开始
Ever since that day,
就一直有人来说他们给了曼德勒钱
I got people showing up saying they got the Mandalay deal
并且威胁要起诉我
and threatening to sue.
我们有理由相信
Well, we have reason to believe
曼德勒是同伙作案
that Mandalay was working with a partner.
还有别人联系过你吗
Did anyone else contact you?
没有
Uh, no.
这件事过后  再没人来过这里
And when the tents folded up, it was radio silence.
但是我联系了其他的一些发展商
But I did call some of the other developers,
果不其然  这个叫曼德勒的家伙
and sure enough, this Mandalay guy,
他也带过一堆客户去他们的楼盘
he brought caravans to their properties.
现在他们也在面对同样的混乱
Now they're dealing with the same mess.
你有宣传册子吗
Do you have any brochures?
我正在找房子  我原先的地方炸掉了
I'm looking for a place. Mine blew up.
每人骗一万
10 grand a pop
在泽西州到处骗
all over Jersey.
很快就是一大笔钱了
That adds up quick.
我不明白在德里克被杀当晚
I don't understand why Derek was still working
他为什么还要去做脱衣舞男
as a stripper the night that he was killed
如果他参与了这么赚钱的一个骗局
if he was involved in a scam
何必还要去跳脱衣舞呢
that was raking in that much money.
因为他不是最终收钱的那个人
Because he wasn't the one raking in all the dough.
他只是个演员  就是个靠长相
He was just the actor, hired for his looks
-靠性格骗钱的幌子  -所以一直以来
- and his personality to charm the investors.  - So all along,
德里克看着他的同伙把钱存进银行
Derek sees his partner taking the money to the bank...
可当他惹上了那帮摩托党以后
and when he gets in trouble with the bikers
他突然间需要现金
and suddenly he needs cash...
他从银行账户里偷拿了他需要的两万五
He raids the bank account for the 25 grand that he needs,
然后被他的同伙发现了
and his partner figures it out.
于是他的同伙跟他发生了激烈的对质
Which leads to a heated confrontation
他承认借了这笔钱
where he admits to borrowing the money,
但是  但是他说他要退出这场骗局
but...but he says he's pulling out of the scam.
知道了  谢谢
Got it. Thanks.
莱恩和埃斯波西托做了些调查
Ryan and Esposito did a little bit of digging,
他们找到了德里克用来取钱的那个
and they found the real owner of the Sunfire account
太阳火账户的真正所有人
that Derek used to withdraw the money.
太阳火的公司注册证书
The articles of incorporation
是由我们那位热爱兰花的寡妇
were signed by our very own orchid-loving widow --
瑞贝卡·达顿签的
Rebecca Dalton.
不是吧
Shut the front door.
贝克特  你确定吗
Beckett, you sure about this?
头儿  都白纸黑字在这摆着呢
Sir, it's all right here in black and white.
我们追踪房地产诈骗案中的金钱去向
We tracked the money from the real estate scam
查到了一个在开曼群岛的海外账户
to this offshore account in the Cayman islands.
这么说德里克决定不再扮演曼德勒
So Derek decides he's done playing the Mandalay role,
但是因为他知道的太多了
and because he knows too much,
所以唯一的选择就是杀了他灭口
the only option is to kill him.
你是对的
Hey. You were right.
我证实了瑞贝卡·达顿的下落
I was able to confirm Rebecca Dalton's whereabouts.
去申请搜查令  搜查杀人凶器
Get a warrant to search for the murder weapon.
作为一个
As someone who's written just about
写书无数的作家来说
every ending in the book,
我可以说"太精彩了"吗
can I just say...amazing?
等犯人认罪了再说也不迟
You can say that after we get the confession.
达顿女士  我们仔细查过了你的经济状况
Ms. Dalton, we did a thorough search of your finances.
自你丈夫过世后
You've lost quite a lot of money
你损失了一大笔钱
since your husband passed away.
我的委托人不需要澄清她的花费习惯
My client doesn't need to defend her spending habits.
如果这与案情有关  她就需要作出解释
She does if it's relevant to my case.
我的钱跟德里克的死有什么关系
What does my money have to do with Derek's death?
实际上  有很大关系
Everything, actually.
你投资了一个从未上架的服装生产线
Let's see, there is a clothing line that never took off,
还有一个失败的珠宝生意
a, uh, failed jewelry business.
还要我继续说下去吗
I mean, should I go on?
这些不能说明我是杀人犯呀
That doesn't make me a murderer.
用不了多久
Well, it was only a matter of time
你的钱就会败光的
until all the money was gone.
德里克很帅  很有魅力
Derek was handsome, he was charming.
你知道他是个优秀的演员
You knew he was a decent actor.
他很适合去向投资者们推荐
It made him the perfect guy to present investors
一个无人能敌的投资机会
with an opportunity they couldn't refuse.
这只是你们的大胆假设
This is wildly speculative,
而且你们的指控毫无根据
and your allegations are baseless.
德里克从一个叫做太阳火的银行账户里
Derek took 25 grand from an account
取了两万五千美金  这账户一开始
that initially led us in circles --
让我们的调查陷入僵局  但现在
The Sunfire account.
这不可能  这都不是我签的
Well, this isn't possible. I didn't even sign this.
瑞贝卡  我建议你不要再多说了
Rebecca, I'm advising you, don't say another word.
等一下  九月二十九号
Wait a minute. September 29th?
我那天都不在国内
I wasn't even in the country.
我们知道
We know.
这个注册证书签署的那天
The date it was signed?
正值巴黎时装周
Smack-dab in the middle of Paris fashion week.
我知道任何一个称职的
I knew that any former model
前任模特都会去参加时装周的
worth her salt would've been there,
当然了  我们也查过航空公司的记录
and of course, after checking flight records,
你当时确实在巴黎
you were in paris.
没错  就当你在巴黎喝着香槟的时候
Yes, and while you were drinking champagne,
你的律师用你的资料设立了这个账户
your lawyer was using his access to your information
以你的名义招摇撞骗
to create a scam in your name.
他还从你这偷钱
Oh, he was also stealing from you,
把你的钱都转到了他的海外账户
funneling the money into his offshore account.
所以你的那些生意才会失败
That's why your businesses failed.
他背着你给德里克提供了一个工作机会
He offered Derek a job behind your back
那就是扮演杰西·曼德勒
to play Jesse Mandalay.
他开的价钱很高
The money was decent,
但是当那些摩托党找上德里克之后
but when the bikers came after Derek,
他需要更多的钱
he needed more.
天啊  迈克尔  你干了什么
Oh, my god. Michael, what did you do?
当你发现德里克未经许可
When you found out that
就从账户里取了钱之后
Derek made an unauthorized withdrawal,
你去找他对质
you confronted him,
但是他知道你不可能去报警
but he knew that you couldn't go to the cops,
于是他说他想退出
so he told you that he wanted out.
你担心他会揭穿你的骗局
You couldn't afford him exposing your fraud,
于是你跟踪他出了家门
so you followed him from his apartment,
然后再于当晚将他杀害
and then killed him that night.
我不会再多说一个字了
I'm not saying another word.
你要请律师吗
Do you want a lawyer...
还是你想找个演员来扮演律师
or do you want to hire an actor to play one for you?
你那个艰苦奋斗的演员案怎么样了
So what happened with your struggling actor case?
他们在律师的办公室
Well, they found the murder weapon
找到了凶器
at the lawyer's office.
他为了达成庭外协议而招供了
He confessed in an effort to cut a deal.
天啊  太令人难过了
Oh, god. It's so sad.
那可怜的孩子只是想转运而已
The poor kid was just trying to catch a break,
却一直霉运连连
and he kept stepping in the dog poo.
你该把这句话绣在枕头上
You should stitch that on to a pillow.
亲爱的  你回来啦
Oh! Hey, sweetie.
咱们家诞生了一位桑德拉·狄吗[《火爆浪子》的女主角]
Do we have a Sandra Dee in our midst?
我没被选上
I didn't get the part.
宝贝儿
Oh, honey.
这是对于你来说  最好的一件事了
This is...the best thing that has ever happened to you.
-什么  -失败正是成功之母
- Wh --  - Rejection is the bedrock of a great acting career.
一个演员就是要在挫折中成长
Until an actor has suffered, he hasn't really lived.
谢谢  奶奶
Thanks, gram.
不客气
You're welcome.
还有  试镜就像是找男人
And besides, auditions are like men.
错过这个  转角处还会遇到下一个
There's another one right around the corner.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我们需要雪糕来缓解伤痛  笨蛋
Oh, we need ice cream to ease the pain, stat.
我去转角的便利店
I'm going to the corner store.
我很遗憾 宝贝
I am sorry, sweetie.
我能坦白一件事吗
Can I admit something?
-当然  -跟凯莉争这个角色
- Always.  - Going up against Kelly
让我意识到  我根本不想要这个角色
made me realize, I didn't really want the part.
我能看出她有多想要那个角色
I could see how hungry she was,
而我又不想让奶奶失望
and I didn't want to disappoint gram,
但是我就是没她那么喜欢演戏
but I don't love it the way she does.
也许和奶奶会说的相反  你就不是这块料
Well, maybe it's not "in your bones", as gram would say.
你肯去尝试  我已经感到很骄傲了
I am proud of you for trying.
谢谢  老爸  而且坏事变好事
Thanks, dad. And there's a silver lining.
在角色公布了以后
After the announcement,
戏剧老师让我做舞台监督
the drama teacher offered me stage manager.
这更适合我
It's way more my style,
而且我还可以继续参加其他课后兴趣班
and I get to keep all my after-school clubs.
我的小优等生
My little overachiever.
祝贺你没有得到那个角色
Well, congratulations on not getting the part.
是什么这么香
Mmm. What smells good?
来帮帮我  洗一下
Come help me. Wash up...